NYSUT General Officers Records 6174/017
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Representative Assemblies; Reports; Correspondence (Box 2)
  - Speeches-Chuck Santelli, 1988-1998 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Outline for speech on educational reform, November 22, 1998; memo to Santelli and others re (lack of) value of a GED diploma, noting GED did not address ability to function well in a group (increased chance of getting a job over a dropout: 5%; increase in wages over those of a dropout: 8%), December 15, 1998; memo from Harry Lampman to Chuck Santelli about attached outline of speech on Compact for Learning, September 17, 1992; analysis of average cost of a classroom of 25 students, with cover memo to Santelli, December 11, 1991; memo to Santelli with statistics re relationship between poverty and achievement, February 10, 1992; speech for Carmen Alvarez, United Federation of Teachers Vice President at Large for Special Education, apparently to hearing committee, n.d.; outline of speech re shared decision-making, n.d.; outline of talking points for Teacher Center meeting, August 13, 1990; outline of taking points re professionalization at Capital District Regional Education Conference, May 29, 1990; Teacher Center fact sheet, c. 1989; outline, Future of Education: Teacher Centers, October 21, 1989; outline for presentation at Washington, Warren, Hamilton, Essex BOCES, December 18, 1989; Remarks by Paul F. Cole, Secretary-Treasurer, New York State AFL-CIP at the Eighteenth Annual Statewide Conference of Local Administrators of Occupational Education, February 8, 1990; speech by Al Shanker, President UFT, "Asking the Right Questions," re restructuring, delivered at AFT's QuEST '89, July 21, 1989; speech for New York State Congress of Parents and Teachers, "Teaching As a Profession," with cover note to Santelli from Harry Lampman, c. 1988; outline of talking points for BOCES conference, October 21, 1988; chapter by Albert Shanker, "The Case for Public School Sponsorship of Early Childhood Education Revisited," from Early Schooling: The National Debate (Kagan & Zigler, eds., Yale University Press, 1987); outline re early childhood education for Task Force on Early Childhood Services, November 1988; packet of materials prepared for presentation by Emil Voigt at Hofstra Education Forum, re Task Force on the Teaching Profession, with cover memo from Harry Lampman, February 28, 1989; handwritten outlines
  - Antonia Cortese-Testimony, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Testimony of Antonia Cortese, First Vice President, New York State United Teachers, to the Board of Regents on the Regents Legislative Proposals, September 11, 1987, and September 5, 1986, with appendix to September 5, 1986, testimony, NYSUT Position on Selected Items in the 1987 Regents Legislative Program; testimony to the Board of Regents on Class Size and Teaching Load, June 19, 1985; list of Cortese biographical facts
  - Antonia Cortese-Chronological File, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    January 2001 - December 2001. Letters to officials at the State Education Department, local presidents, individuals, re Regents testing standards, other issues
  - Antonia Cortese-Chronological File, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    January 2002 - December 2002. Letters to officials at the State Education Department re access by teaching assistants to information re students with disabilities, report on middle school education, Edison Schools, Inc.; letters to local teacher associations re conferences, other issues
  - Herb Magidson Testimony, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Testimony of Herb Magidson, Executive Vice President, New York State United Teachers, to the Senate Education Committee on State Aid for Education, 1987: Services for Children-at-Risk in New York State's Schools, February 10, 1987